Usama Aslam

Lahore District, Punjab, Pakistan



uxamaaxlam7@gmail.com



03015320256



linkedin.com/in/usama-aslam-here

Summary

Multi Stack Web development hands on experience of two years.

Beings a Computer science graduate I have problem solving skills, and software engineering ethics including Object Oriented Analysis and design.

Good familiarity with Machine learning NLP and computer vision algorithms.

Experience



Web Application Developer

Allied Consultants

Oct 2020 - Present (9 months +)

Development with ReactJs/MaterialUI (October-2020 to February-2021):

B2B, Buisiness Intelligence and Risk Analysis Web-Application: 'TalisAi.com'

Code Refactoring & development with ReactJs/MaterialUI (March-2021 to May-2021):

US based biggest Online Lawyer booking Web-Application: 'Booklawyer.com'

Developed Hublot Cross-platform Application with React Native (Hublot: A Swiss luxury watch brand)

Currently working on Ordercircle.com with Laravel and VueJs

Web Developer

Asian Solutions Pvt. Ltd. Mar 2020 - Oct 2020 (8 months)

Education



University of Engineering and Technology, Lahore

Bachelor of Science in Computer Science, Computer Science 2017 - 2021

Punjab Group of Colleges

Mathematics and Computer Science 2015 - 2017

American Lycetuff School

Matriculation, Computer Science 2010 - 2015

Skills

Web Development • Computer Science • Artificial Intelligence (AI) • Machine Learning • MERN Stack • React.js • JavaScript • Laravel • React Native • Microsoft Azure

Honors & Awards



Clean Code Competition Winner

2019

Intra city Code competition based on OOP concepts



Career Counseling

2018

Career counselling workshop for the matric and intermediate students in order to let them identify their respective field of interest and domain they really need to go.



First Aid Trainer

2019

Trained hundreds of students in colleges and universities for First Aid and disaster management.